Guide to the Records of the Office of the Assistant Executive Vice-President, Frederick H. Jackson RG 6.5.1
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of Assistant Executive Vice-President, Frederick H. Jackson
Bulk, 1964-1967
1962-1968
RG 6.5.1
New York University Archives
5.5 linear feet
Frederick Herbert Jackson served as the Assistant Executive Vice President at NYU beginning in 1964. In this position, Jackson supervised instruction in the humanities and the social sciences. He held this position until he was appointed Vice President for Humanities and Social Sciences in 1966.
Jackson, Frederick Herbert, 1919-
Access Restrictions
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Additionally, this collection is in off-site storage. Please contact the repository for access.
Biography
Frederick Herbert Jackson became the Assistant Executive Vice President at NYU in 1964 and held this position until he was appointed Vice President for Humanities and Social Sciences in 1966. While Assistant Executive Vice President, Jackson supervised instruction in the humanities and the social sciences.
Frederick H. Jackson was born in New Haven, Connecticut, on May 16, 1919. He received his AB in English literature from Brown University in 1941. At Brown Jackson was a John Hay scholar and a member of Phi Beta Kappa. In 1948 and 1950, he received his AM and Ph.D., respectively, from the University of Pennsylvania. There Jackson was a Harrison Fellow in American Civilization from 1947-1948. Jackson's areas of academic interests included American intellectual history and the history of American higher education.
Jackson taught at Marietta College (1948-1950) and later at the University of Illinois (1950-1955) in the Division of General Studies as an instructor and Assistant Professor of History. He was also the Executive Assistant (1955-1957) and the Executive Associate (1957-1964) of the Carnegie Corporation of New York before coming to NYU.
Jackson's other achievements and accomplishments include studying at Harvard (1941-1942) as a University Fellow in American Civilization and serving in the Air Force during World War II. He was an instructor in bombsight and automatic flight control from 1943-1944 and a statistical control officer from 1944-1946.
He married Eleanor S. Whittemore in 1942.
His numerous articles and reviews have been published in journals such as the American Historical Review, The Progressive, and The Historian, and his book, Simeon Eben Baldwin: Lawyer, Scholar, Statesman, was published by Columbia University Press in 1955. Jackson received a Bicentennial Medallion from Brown in 1965 for his academic achievements.
He left his post at NYU in 1967 to become the fourth president of Clark University.
Scope and Content Note
This collection houses correspondence, memoranda, reports, and proposals generated and received by Frederick H. Jackson during his time as Assistant Executive Vice President. Documents date from 1962 to 1968, though the bulk of the records date from the 1964-1967 period. The folders in the collection are arranged alphabetically.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
The files are grouped into one series:
Administrative records
Jackson, Frederick Herbert, 1919-; New York University.; Phi Beta Kappa.; Whittemore, Eleanor S.; Correspondence.; Memorandums.; New York (N.Y.); Proposals.; Reports.
- Series I: Administrative records
  - Academic Administrators – Vitaes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administration/President – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Administration/Vice-President – Proposals, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Administration/Vice-President for Business Affairs, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administration/Vice-President for Humanities and Social Sciences – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administration/Vice-President for Medical Affairs – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administration/Vice-President for Scientific Affairs – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administration/Vice-President for University Relations – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Admissions Office – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - All-University Department: Biology – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - All-University Department: Chemistry – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - All-University Department: Classics – Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - All-University Department: Economics – Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - All-University Department: English – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - All-University Department: Geology – Memoranda, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - All-University Department: Germanic Languages and Literature – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - All-University Department: Government and International Relations – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - All-University Department: Head Meetings Minutes, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - All-University Department: History – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - All-University Department: Mathematic – Memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - All-University Department: Music – Memoranda, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - All-University Department: Philosophy – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - All-University Department: Physics – Proposals, Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - All-University Department: Psychology – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - All-University Department: Romance Languages and Literature – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - All-University Department: Slavic Languages and Literature – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - All-University Department: Sociology – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Council on Education, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - American Council on Education – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Budget Advisory Group – Minutes, Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Budget Advisory Group – Minutes, Reports, Correspondence, Memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Budget Advisory Group – Minutes, Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Bylaws – Drafts, Memoranda, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Chinese – Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Computing Services Agency Committee – Drafts, Reports, Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Council, University Heights – Reports, Minutes, Memoranda, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Council, Washington Square – Correspondence, Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Deans, Committee of – Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Deans Council – Minutes, Reports, Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Distinguished Professors – Correspondence and Memoranda, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Executive Safety Council – Memoranda, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Club (NYU) at Washington Square, Inc. – Minutes, Correspondence, Memoranda, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Foundations/Carnegie Corporation of New York – Correspondence, Memoranda, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Foundations/Carnegie Corporation: Institute for Computer Research in the Humanities – Correspondence and Reports, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Foundations/Education and World Affairs – Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Foundations/Miscellaneous – Correspondence, Reports, Memoranda, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Foundations/National Science Foundation – Correspondence, Proposals, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Foundations/National Science Foundation – Correspondence, Proposals, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Foundations/The Rockefeller Foundation – Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Foundations/Science and Technology Foundation of New York State – Correspondence, Proposals, Memoranda, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Work, University Commission on – Reports, Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965: Joint Proposal with Norfolk State – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965: Joint Proposal with Norfolk State, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Human Rights, World Center on – Proposal, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Humanities, Institute for Computer Research in the – Correspondence, Reports, Minutes, Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Humanities, Institute for Computer Research in the – Minutes, Correspondence, Reports, Proposals, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - International Student Center – Memoranda, Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - International Studies Center – Correspondence, Reports, Memoranda, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - International Studies Center – Correspondence, Report, Memoranda, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - International Studies Center – Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - International Studies Center – Minutes, Correspondence, Proposals, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - International Studies Center – Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Medical Center: Dixon Committee Business Transactions, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Modern Language Association – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Defense Education Act – Correspondence, Memoranda, Application, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Defense Education Act – Memoranda, Reports, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - National Defense Education Act – Memoranda, Correspondence, Proposals, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - National Defense Education Act – Correspondence, Application, Memoranda, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - National Defense Education Act – Memoranda, Reports, Applications, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - National Collegiate Honors Council – Correspondence, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - National Medal of Honor – Correspondence, Profiles, Memoranda, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - New York Theological Seminary, Affiliation with – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Planning and Supervising Architect, Director of – Minutes, Memoranda, Plans, Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Policy/Compensation for Extra Work – Memoranda, Policy, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Policy/Flat Fee – Memoranda, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Policy/Graduate Work at University Heights – Memoranda, Reports, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Policy/Promotions and Salary Recommendations – Memoranda, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Policy/Sabbatical Leave – Memoranda, Application, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Press Releases – General, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Proposal/Arts, School of the – Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Proposal/Computer Research Institute in the Humanities – Correspondence, Proposals, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Proposal/Continuing Education Center in Westchester County – Correspondence, Proposals, Memoranda, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Proposal/Continuing Education Center in Westchester County – Correspondence, Proposals, Memoranda, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Proposal/International Studies Center – Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Proposal/International Studies Center – Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Proposal/Metropolitan Leadership Program – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Proposal/Metropolitan Leadership Program – Correspondence, Proposal, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Proposal/Miscellaneous – Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Proposal/Miscellaneous – Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - New York University Press – Minutes, Memoranda, Proposal, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Publications – General, 1964-1967 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Publications Requisition – Memoranda, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Registrar, Office of – Memoranda, Reports, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Renovations – Memoranda, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Research Services, Office of – Memoranda, Correspondence, Proposals, Application, 1962-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Research Services, Office of – Proposals, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Schools/Arts, School of – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Schools/Arts, School of – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Schools/Arts, School of – Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports, 1966-1968 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Schools/Arts, School of – Correspondence, Memoranda, Reports, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Schools/Commerce, Account and Finance, School of – Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Schools/Continuing Education, School of – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Schools/Continuing Education, School of, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Schools/Continuing Education, School of (and Extension Services) – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Schools/Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences – Correspondence, Memoranda, Minutes, Proposals, 1965-1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Schools/Dentistry, College of – Budgets, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Schools/Education, School of – Memoranda, Proposals, 1964-1965 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Schools/Education, School of – Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Schools/Education, School of – Policy, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Schools/Education, School of – Memoranda, Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Schools/Education, School of – Proposals, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Schools/Engineering and Science, School of – Memoranda, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Schools/Fine Arts Institute – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Schools/Arts and Science, Graduate School of – Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Schools/Business Administration, Graduate School of – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Schools/Law School – Memoranda, Correspondence, Application, 1964-1966 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Schools/Medicine, School of – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Schools/Physical Medicine and Rehabilitation, Institute of – Memoranda, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Schools/Public Administration, Graduate School of – Memoranda, Proposals, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Schools/Public Administration, Graduate School of – Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Schools/Retail Management, Institute of – Memoranda, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Schools/Social Work, Graduate School of – Memoranda, Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Schools/Arts and Science, University College of – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Schools/Arts and Science, Washington Square College of – Memoranda, Correspondence, Reports, 1964-1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Schools/Arts and Science, Washington Square College of – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Teacher Education, All-University Commission on – Minutes, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Undergraduate Recruitment, Admissions, and Scholarship, Commission on -, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - University Valley – Memoranda, Correspondence, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Urban Studies Consultants – Reports, Memoranda, Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 14)